<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
	<character>
		<version>37</version>
		<uid>2176</uid>
		<name>Undertow (Ranger)</name>
		<race>
			<name>Locathah</name>
			<age>28</age>
			<height>6 ft. 2 in.</height>
			<weight>170 lbs/</weight>
			<eyes>Yellow</eyes>
			<skin>Venom Green</skin>
			<hair>N/a</hair>
			<feat>
				<name>Natural Armor</name>
				<text>You have tough, scaly skin. When you aren’t wearing armor, your AC is 12 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Observant &#38; Athletic</name>
				<text>You have proficiency in the Athletics and Perception skills.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Leviathan Will</name>
				<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, frightened, paralyzed, poisoned, stunned, or put to sleep.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Limited Amphibiousness</name>
				<text>You can breathe air and water, but you need to be submerged at least once every 4 hours to avoid suffocating.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Speed</name>
				<text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet, and you have a swim speed of 30 feet.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>You can speak, read, and write Aquan and Common.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<value>2</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>1</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<proficiency>103</proficiency>
			<proficiency>111</proficiency>
		</race>
		<class>
			<id>1168</id>
			<name>Ranger (Beast)</name>
			<level>9</level>
			<hd>3</hd>
			<hdCurrent>9</hdCurrent>
			<wealth>5d4x10</wealth>
			<proficiency>110</proficiency>
			<proficiency>108</proficiency>
			<proficiency>101</proficiency>
			<proficiency>1</proficiency>
			<proficiency>116</proficiency>
			<proficiency>0</proficiency>
			<numClassSkills>3</numClassSkills>
			<armor>light armor, medium armor, shields</armor>
			<weapons>simple weapons, martial weapons</weapons>
			<tools>none</tools>
			<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			<slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields
Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
Tools: none
Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) scale mail or (b) leather armor
• (a) two shortswords or (b) two simple melee weapons
• (a) a dungeoneer&#39;s pack or (b) an explorer&#39;s pack
• A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows

Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Favored Enemy</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy.
	beasts
	You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.
	When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice that is spoken by your favored enemies, if they speak one at all.
	You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language, at 6th and 14th level. As you gain levels, your choices should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Natural Explorer</name>
				<text>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions.
coast, swamp.

When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you&#39;re proficient in.
	While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits:

• Difficult terrain doesn&#39;t slow your group&#39;s travel.
• Your group can&#39;t become lost except by magical means.
• Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.
• If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.
• When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.
• While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.

	You choose additional favored terrain types at 6th and 10th level.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list.

Spell Slots
The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#39;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot.

Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher
You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list.
	You learn an additional ranger spell of your choice at each odd numbered level thereafter. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.
	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Spellcasting Ability
Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Archery, Defense, Dueling, Mariner, or Two-Weapon Fighting. You can&#39;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
				<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
				<optional>1</optional>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Ranger Archetype</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate: Beast Master, Deep Stalker, or Hunter. Your choice grants features at 3rd level, and again at 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Primeval Awareness</name>
				<text>Beginning at 3rd level, you can use your action and expend one ranger spell slot to focus your awareness on the region around you. For 1 minute per level of the spell slot you expend, you can sense whether the following types of creatures are present within 1 mile of you (or within up to 6 miles if you are in your favored terrain): aberrations, celestials, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead. This feature doesn&#39;t reveal the creatures&#39; location or number.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Ranger Conclave: Beast Master</name>
				<text>The Beast Master archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world. United in focus, beast and ranger work as one to fight the monstrous foes that threaten civilization and the wilderness alike. Emulating the Beast Master archetype means committing yourself to this ideal, working in partnership with an animal as its companion and friend.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
				<optional>1</optional>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Beast Master: Ranger&#39;s Companion</name>
				<text>You gain a beast companion that accompanies you on your adventures and is trained to fight alongside you. Choose a beast that is no larger than Medium and that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower. Add your proficiency bonus to the beast&#39;s AC, attack rolls, and damage rolls, as well as to any saving throws and skills it is proficient in. Its hit point maximum equals its normal maximum or four times your ranger level, whichever is higher.
	The beast obeys your commands as best as it can. It takes its turn on your initiative, though it doesn&#39;t take an action unless you command it to. On your turn, you can verbally command the beast where to move (no action required by you). You can use your action to verbally command it to take the Attack, Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action. Once you have the Extra Attack feature, you can make one weapon attack yourself when you command the beast to take the Attack action.
	If you are incapacitated or absent, your beast companion acts on its own, focusing on protecting you and itself. It never requires your command to use its reaction, such as when making an opportunity attack.
	Like any creature, the beast can spend hit dice during a short rest.
	While traveling through your favored terrain with only the beast, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.
	If the beast dies, you can obtain another one by spending 8 hours magically bonding with another beast that isn&#39;t hostile to you, either the same type of beast as before or a different one.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
				<optional>1</optional>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Additional Favored Terrains</name>
				<text>You gain an additional favored terrain.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Additional Favored Enemy</name>
				<text>You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language. Your choice should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Beast Master: Exceptional Training</name>
				<text>On any of your turns when your beast companion doesn&#39;t attack, you can use a bonus action to command the beast to take the Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action on its turn.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
				<optional>1</optional>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Land&#39;s Stride</name>
				<text>Starting at 8th level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.
	In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<autolevel>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
					<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields
Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
Tools: none
Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Equipment</name>
					<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) scale mail or (b) leather armor
• (a) two shortswords or (b) two simple melee weapons
• (a) a dungeoneer&#39;s pack or (b) an explorer&#39;s pack
• A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows

Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Favored Enemy</name>
					<text>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy.
	Choose a type of favored enemy: aberrations, beasts, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, giants, monstrosities, oozes, plants, or undead. Alternatively, you can select two races of humanoid (such as gnolls and orcs) as favored enemies.
	You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.
	When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice that is spoken by your favored enemies, if they speak one at all.
	You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language, at 6th and 14th level. As you gain levels, your choices should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Natural Explorer</name>
					<text>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you&#39;re proficient in.
	While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits:

• Difficult terrain doesn&#39;t slow your group&#39;s travel.
• Your group can&#39;t become lost except by magical means.
• Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.
• If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.
• When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.
• While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.

	You choose additional favored terrain types at 6th and 10th level.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>2</level>
				<slots>0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Spellcasting</name>
					<text>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list.

Spell Slots
The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#39;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot.

Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher
You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list.
	You learn an additional ranger spell of your choice at each odd numbered level thereafter. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.
	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.

Spellcasting Ability
Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style</name>
					<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Archery, Defense, Dueling, Mariner, or Two-Weapon Fighting. You can&#39;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style: Archery</name>
					<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
					<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
					<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
					<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter</name>
					<text>When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.

This Fighting Style is from Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style: Mariner</name>
					<text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.

This Fighting Style is from Unearthed Arcana: Watborne Adventures, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter</name>
					<text>As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>3</level>
				<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ranger Archetype</name>
					<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate: Beast Master, Deep Stalker, or Hunter. Your choice grants features at 3rd level, and again at 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Primeval Awareness</name>
					<text>Beginning at 3rd level, you can use your action and expend one ranger spell slot to focus your awareness on the region around you. For 1 minute per level of the spell slot you expend, you can sense whether the following types of creatures are present within 1 mile of you (or within up to 6 miles if you are in your favored terrain): aberrations, celestials, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead. This feature doesn&#39;t reveal the creatures&#39; location or number.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Ranger Conclave: Beast Master</name>
					<text>The Beast Master archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world. United in focus, beast and ranger work as one to fight the monstrous foes that threaten civilization and the wilderness alike. Emulating the Beast Master archetype means committing yourself to this ideal, working in partnership with an animal as its companion and friend.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Beast Master: Ranger&#39;s Companion</name>
					<text>You gain a beast companion that accompanies you on your adventures and is trained to fight alongside you. Choose a beast that is no larger than Medium and that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower. Add your proficiency bonus to the beast&#39;s AC, attack rolls, and damage rolls, as well as to any saving throws and skills it is proficient in. Its hit point maximum equals its normal maximum or four times your ranger level, whichever is higher.
	The beast obeys your commands as best as it can. It takes its turn on your initiative, though it doesn&#39;t take an action unless you command it to. On your turn, you can verbally command the beast where to move (no action required by you). You can use your action to verbally command it to take the Attack, Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action. Once you have the Extra Attack feature, you can make one weapon attack yourself when you command the beast to take the Attack action.
	If you are incapacitated or absent, your beast companion acts on its own, focusing on protecting you and itself. It never requires your command to use its reaction, such as when making an opportunity attack.
	Like any creature, the beast can spend hit dice during a short rest.
	While traveling through your favored terrain with only the beast, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.
	If the beast dies, you can obtain another one by spending 8 hours magically bonding with another beast that isn&#39;t hostile to you, either the same type of beast as before or a different one.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>4</level>
				<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>5</level>
				<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Extra Attack</name>
					<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>6</level>
				<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Additional Favored Terrains</name>
					<text>You gain an additional favored terrain.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Additional Favored Enemy</name>
					<text>You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language. Your choice should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>7</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Beast Master: Exceptional Training</name>
					<text>On any of your turns when your beast companion doesn&#39;t attack, you can use a bonus action to command the beast to take the Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action on its turn.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>8</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Land&#39;s Stride</name>
					<text>Starting at 8th level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.
	In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>9</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>10</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Hide in Plain Sight</name>
					<text>Starting at 10th level, you can spend 1 minute creating camouflage for yourself. You must have access to fresh mud, dirt, plants, soot, and other naturally occurring materials with which to create your camouflage.
	Once you are camouflaged in this way, you can try to hide by pressing yourself up against a solid surface, such as a tree or wall, that is at least as tall and wide as you are. You gain a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks as long as you remain there without moving or taking actions. Once you move or take an action or a reaction, you must camouflage yourself again to gain this benefit.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Additional Favored Terrains</name>
					<text>You gain an additional favored terrain.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>11</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Beast Master: Bestial Fury</name>
					<text>Your beast companion can make two attacks or use Multiattack (if available) when you command it to use the Attack action.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>12</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>13</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>14</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Vanish</name>
					<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can&#39;t be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Additional Favored Enemy</name>
					<text>You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language. Your choice should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>15</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Beast Master: Share Spells</name>
					<text>Beginning at 15th level, when you cast a spell targeting yourself, you can also affect your beast companion with the spell if the beast is within 30 feet of you.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>16</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>17</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>18</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Feral Senses</name>
					<text>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can&#39;t see. When you attack a creature you can&#39;t see, your inability to see it doesn&#39;t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it. You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn&#39;t hidden from you and you aren&#39;t blinded or deafened.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>19</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>20</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Foe Slayer</name>
					<text>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter of your enemies. Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make against one of your favored enemies. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<spellAbility>4</spellAbility>
			<spell>
				<name>Spike Growth</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>seven sharp thorns or seven small twigs, each sharpened to a point</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>The ground in a 20-foot radius centered on a point within range twists and sprouts hard spikes and thorns. The area becomes difficult terrain for the duration. When a creature moves into or within the area, it takes 2d4 piercing damage for every 5 feet it travels.

The transformation of the ground is camouflaged to look natural. Any creature that can&#39;t see the area at the time the spell is case must make a Wisdom (Perception) check against your spell save DC to recognize the terrain as hazardous before entering it.</text>
				<roll>2d4</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Lesser Restoration</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature and can end either one disease or one condition afflicting it. The condition can be blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Pass without Trace</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>ashes from a burned leaf of mistletoe and a sprig of spruce</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>A veil of shadows and silence radiates from you, masking you and your companions from detection. For the duration, each creature you choose within 30 feet of you (including you) has a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks and can&#39;t be tracked except by magical means. A creature that receives this bonus leaves behind no tracks or other traces of its passage.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Speak with Animals</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You gain the ability to comprehend and verbally communicate with beasts for the duration. The knowledge and awareness of many beasts is limited by their intelligence, but at minimum, beasts can give you information about nearby locations and monsters, including whatever they can perceive or have perceived within the past day. You might be able to persuade a beast to perform a small favor for you, at the DM&#39;s discretion.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Conjure Animals</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<level>3</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You summon fey spirits that take the form of beasts and appear in unoccupied spaces that you can see within range. Choose one of the following options for what appears.

• One beast of challenge rating 2 or lower

• Two beasts of challenge rating 1 or lower

• Four beasts of challenge rating 1/2 or lower

• Eight beasts of challenge rating 1/4 or lower

Each beast is also considered fey, and it disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.

The summoned creatures are friendly to you and your companions. Roll initiative for the summoned creatures as a group, which has its own turns. They obey any verbal commands that you issue to them (no action required by you). If you don&#39;t issue any commands to them, they defend themselves from hostile creatures, but otherwise take no actions. The DM has the creatures&#39; statistics.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using certain higher-level spell slots, you choose one of the summoning options above, and more creatures appear - twice as many with a 5th-level slot, three times as many with a 7th-level slot, and four times as many with a 9th-level slot.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Barkskin</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a handful of oak bark</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature. Until the spell ends, the target&#39;s skin has a rough, bark-like appearance, and the target&#39;s AC can&#39;t be less than 16, regardless of what kind of armor it is wearing.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Hunter&#39;s Mark</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>90 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You choose a creature you can see within range and mystically mark it as your quarry. Until the spell ends, you deal an extra 1d6 damage to the target whenever you hit it with a weapon attack, and you have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Wisdom (Survival) check you make to find it. If the target drops to 0 hit points before this spell ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to mark a new creature.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd or 4th level, you can maintain your concentration on the spell for up to 8 hours. When you use a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can maintain your concentration on the spell for up to 24 hours.</text>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Zephyr Strike</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You move like the wind. Until the spell ends, your movement doesn&#39;t provoke opportunity attacks.

Once before the spell ends, you can give yourself advantage on one weapon attack roll on your turn. That attack deals an extra 1d8 force damage on a hit. Whether you hit or miss, your walking speed increases by 30 feet until the end of that turn.

This spell can be found in Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything</text>
				<roll>1d8</roll>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
		</class>
		<background>
			<id>1411</id>
			<name>Outlander</name>
			<feat>
				<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Athletics, Survival</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
				<text>One type of musical instrument</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>One of your choice</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Equipment</name>
				<text>A staff, a hunting trap, a trophy from an animal you killed, a set of traveler&#39;s clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Feature: Wanderer</name>
				<text>You have an excellent memory for maps and geography, and you can always recall the general layout of terrain, settlements, and other features around you. In addition, you can find food and fresh water for yourself and up to five other people each day, provided that the land offers berries, small game, water, and so forth.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<proficiency>103</proficiency>
			<proficiency>117</proficiency>
		</background>
		<xp>48000</xp>
		<unarmed>1</unarmed>
		<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
		<slotsCurrent>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
		<item>
			<name>Shield +1</name>
			<text>Rarity: Uncommon
	While holding this shield, you have a +1 bonus to AC. This bonus is in addition to the shield&#39;s normal bonus to AC.

Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, page 200</text>
			<type>4</type>
			<slot>4</slot>
			<weight>6.0</weight>
			<magic>1</magic>
			<ac>2</ac>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Hand Crossbow</name>
			<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see &#34;Improvised Weapons&#34; later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Loading: Because of the time required to load this weapon, you can fire only one piece of ammunition from it when you use an action, bonus action, or reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon&#39;s normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon&#39;s maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can&#39;t attack a target beyond the weapon&#39;s long range.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>6</type>
			<value>75.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damageType>2</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>25</weaponProperty>
			<weaponRange>30</weaponRange>
			<weaponLongRange>120</weaponLongRange>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Shortsword +2</name>
			<text>Rarity: Rare
	You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.

Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, page 213</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
			<magic>1</magic>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damageType>2</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>10</weaponProperty>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Crossbow Bolts</name>
			<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 150</text>
			<type>7</type>
			<quantity>20</quantity>
			<value>0.05</value>
			<weight>0.075</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Crossbow Bolt Case</name>
			<text>This wooden case can hold up to twenty crossbow bolts.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 151</text>
			<value>1.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<container>
			<label>Explorer&#39;s Pack</label>
			<name>Backpack</name>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Bedroll</name>
				<weight>7.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Mess kit</name>
				<weight>1.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Rations (1 day)</name>
				<quantity>10</quantity>
				<weight>2.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Rope, hempen (50 feet)</name>
				<weight>10.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Goggles of Night</name>
				<text>Rarity: Uncommon
While wearing these dark lenses, you have darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision. wearing the goggles increases its range by 60 feet.

Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide, page 172</text>
				<type>14</type>
				<magic>1</magic>
			</item>
		</container>
		<container>
			<name>Money</name>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Copper (cp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.01</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Silver (sp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.1</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Electrum (ep)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.2</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Gold (gp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>10</quantity>
				<value>1.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Platinum (pp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>10.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<note>
			<name>Proficiencies and Languages</name>
			<text>Aquan, Common, Deep Speech, Elvish, Sahuagin

Herbalism Kit, Poisoner’s Kit</text>
		</note>
		<monster>
			<label>Fluffer</label>
			<name>Sea Lion</name>
			<size>3</size>
			<type>beast</type>
			<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
			<ac>20</ac>
			<armor>natural armor</armor>
			<hd>12d10+24</hd>
			<speed>15 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>
			<savingThrow>
				<ability>1</ability>
				<modifier>6</modifier>
			</savingThrow>
			<savingThrow>
				<ability>2</ability>
				<modifier>8</modifier>
			</savingThrow>
			<skill>
				<id>11</id>
				<modifier>6</modifier>
			</skill>
			<skill>
				<id>3</id>
				<modifier>9</modifier>
			</skill>
			<passive>16</passive>
			<cr>-4</cr>
			<trait>
				<name>Hold Breath</name>
				<text>The sea lion can hold its breath for 15 minutes.</text>
			</trait>
			<trait>
				<name>Water Breathing</name>
				<text>Possesses collar of water breathing</text>
			</trait>
			<action>
				<name>Bite</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (1d8 + 7) piercing damage.</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Bite</name>
					<attackBonus>9</attackBonus>
					<damage>1d8+7</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<action>
				<name>Claws</name>
				<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d4+7) slashing damage, and the target is pushed up to 5 feet away from the sea lion</text>
				<attack>
					<name>Claw</name>
					<attackBonus>9</attackBonus>
					<damage>1d4+7</damage>
				</attack>
			</action>
			<abilities>17,10,14,5,10,12,</abilities>
			<hpMax>36</hpMax>
			<hpCurrent>36</hpCurrent>
		</monster>
		<abilities>10,15,14,12,16,10,</abilities>
		<hpMax>65</hpMax>
		<hpCurrent>65</hpCurrent>
	</character>
</pc>