<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
	<character>
		<version>37</version>
		<uid>2145</uid>
		<name>Keth Silverson</name>
		<race>
			<name>Half-Orc</name>
			<feat>
				<name>Darkvision</name>
				<text>Thanks to your orc blood, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can&#39;t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Menacing</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Relentless Endurance</name>
				<text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can&#39;t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Savage Attacks</name>
				<text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon&#39;s damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Orc. Orc is a harsh, grating language with hard consonants. It has no script of its own but is written in the Dwarvish script.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<value>2</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>2</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<proficiency>107</proficiency>
		</race>
		<class>
			<id>1149</id>
			<name>Rogue (Thief)</name>
			<hd>2</hd>
			<wealth>4d4x10</wealth>
			<proficiency>1</proficiency>
			<proficiency>3</proficiency>
			<proficiency>108</proficiency>
			<proficiency>112</proficiency>
			<proficiency>104</proficiency>
			<proficiency>100</proficiency>
			<numClassSkills>4</numClassSkills>
			<armor>light armor</armor>
			<weapons>simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</weapons>
			<tools>thieves&#39; tools, playing cards, disguise kit</tools>
			<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			<slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor
Weapons: simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords
Tools: thieves&#39; tools
Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword
• (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword
• (a) a burglar&#39;s pack, (b) a dungeoneer&#39;s pack, or (c) an explorer&#39;s pack
• Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves&#39; tools

Alternatively, you may start with 4d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves&#39; tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.
	At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with thieves&#39; tools) to gain this benefit.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
				<proficiency>116</proficiency>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Sneak Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe&#39;s distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.
	You don&#39;t need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn&#39;t incapacitated, and you don&#39;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
	The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown in the Sneak Attack column of the Rogue table.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Thieves&#39; Cant</name>
				<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves&#39; cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves&#39; cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.
	In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves&#39; guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<autolevel>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
					<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor
Weapons: simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords
Tools: thieves&#39; tools
Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Equipment</name>
					<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword
• (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword
• (a) a burglar&#39;s pack, (b) a dungeoneer&#39;s pack, or (c) an explorer&#39;s pack
• Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves&#39; tools

Alternatively, you may start with 4d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Expertise</name>
					<text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves&#39; tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.
	At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with thieves&#39; tools) to gain this benefit.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Sneak Attack</name>
					<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe&#39;s distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.
	You don&#39;t need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn&#39;t incapacitated, and you don&#39;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
	The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown in the Sneak Attack column of the Rogue table.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Thieves&#39; Cant</name>
					<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves&#39; cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves&#39; cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.
	In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves&#39; guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>2</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Cunning Action</name>
					<text>Starting at 2nd level, your quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>3</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Roguish Archetype</name>
					<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you emulate in the exercise of your rogue abilities: Thief, Assassin, or Arcane Trickster, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your archetype choice grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Roguish Archetype: Thief</name>
					<text>You hone your skills in the larcenous arts. Burglars, bandits, cutpurses, and other criminals typically follow this archetype, but so do rogues who prefer to think of themselves as professional treasure seekers, explorers, delvers, and investigators. In addition to improving your agility and stealth, you learn skills useful for delving into ancient ruins, reading unfamiliar languages, and using magic items you normally couldn&#39;t employ.

Your archetype grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Thief: Fast Hands</name>
					<text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, use your thieves&#39; tools to disarm a trap or open a lock, or take the Use an Object action.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Thief: Second-Story Work</name>
					<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the ability to climb faster than normal; climbing no longer costs you extra movement.
	In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>4</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>5</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
					<text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack&#39;s damage against you.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>6</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>7</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Evasion</name>
					<text>Beginning at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon&#39;s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>8</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>9</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Thief: Supreme Sneak</name>
					<text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on a Dexterity (Stealth) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>10</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>11</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Reliable Talent</name>
					<text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>12</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>13</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Thief: Use Magic Device</name>
					<text>By 13th level, you have learned enough about the workings of magic that you can improvise the use of items even when they are not intended for you. You ignore all class, race, and level requirements on the use of magic items.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>14</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Blindsense</name>
					<text>Starting at 14th level, if you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>15</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Slippery Mind</name>
					<text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>16</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>17</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Thief: Thief&#39;s Reflexes</name>
					<text>When you reach 17th level, you have become adept at laying ambushes and quickly escaping danger. You can take two turns during the first round of any combat. You take your first turn at your normal initiative and your second turn at your initiative minus 10. You can&#39;t use this feature when you are surprised.</text>
					<optional>1</optional>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>18</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Elusive</name>
					<text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren&#39;t incapacitated.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>19</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>20</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Stroke of Luck</name>
					<text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.
	Once you use this feature, you can&#39;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
		</class>
		<background>
			<id>1383</id>
			<name>Urchin</name>
			<align>Chaotic good</align>
			<personality>I have trouble saying no to pretty girls.. and made scientists.</personality>
			<ideals>What’s mine is yours, and what’s yours is mine.</ideals>
			<bonds>You know what? What’s mine is actually mine. Give it back.</bonds>
			<flaws>I have problems trusting my allies.</flaws>
			<feat>
				<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Sleight of Hand, Stealth</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Disguise Kit, thieves&#39; tools</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Equipment</name>
				<text>A small knife, a map of the city you grew up in, a pet mouse, a token to remember your parents by, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Feature: City Secrets</name>
				<text>You know the secret patterns and flow to cities and can find passages through the urban sprawl that others would miss. When you are not in combat, you (and companions you lead) can travel between any two locations in the city twice as fast as your speed would normally allow.</text>
				<expanded>0</expanded>
			</feat>
			<proficiency>116</proficiency>
			<proficiency>115</proficiency>
		</background>
		<unarmed>1</unarmed>
		<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
		<slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
		<attack>
			<name>Sneak Attack</name>
			<damage>1d6</damage>
		</attack>
		<tracker>
			<label>Thieves’ Tools</label>
			<type>2</type>
			<formula>1d20+%2+%8+%8</formula>
		</tracker>
		<tracker>
			<label>Relentless Endurance</label>
			<resetType>2</resetType>
			<value>1</value>
			<formula>1</formula>
		</tracker>
		<item>
			<name>Dagger</name>
			<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon&#39;s normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon&#39;s maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can&#39;t attack a target beyond the weapon&#39;s long range.

Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<slot>2</slot>
			<quantity>2</quantity>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d4</damage1H>
			<damageType>2</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty>
			<weaponRange>20</weaponRange>
			<weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Leather Armor</name>
			<text>The breastplate and shoulder protectors of this armor are made of leather that has been stiffened by being boiled in oil. The rest of the armor is made of softer and more flexible materials.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 144</text>
			<type>1</type>
			<slot>5</slot>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>10.0</weight>
			<ac>11</ac>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Thieves&#39; Tools</name>
			<text>This set of tools includes a small file, a set of lock picks, a small mirror mounted on a metal handle, a set of narrow-bladed scissors, and a pair of pliers. Proficiency with these tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make to disarm traps or open locks.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 154</text>
			<value>25.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Set Of Dark Clothes Including A Hood</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Pouch</name>
			<text>A cloth or leather pouch can hold up to 20 sling bullets or 50 blowgun needles, among other things. A compartmentalized pouch for holding spell components is called a component pouch. A pouch can hold up to 1/5 cubic foot or 6 pounds of gear.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>0.5</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<container>
			<label>Burglar&#39;s Pack</label>
			<name>Backpack</name>
			<value>16.0</value>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Bell</name>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Candle</name>
				<quantity>5</quantity>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Crowbar</name>
				<weight>5.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Hammer</name>
				<weight>3.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Piton</name>
				<quantity>10</quantity>
				<weight>0.25</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Lantern, hooded</name>
				<weight>2.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Oil (flask)</name>
				<quantity>2</quantity>
				<weight>1.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Rations (1 day)</name>
				<quantity>5</quantity>
				<weight>2.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Tinderbox</name>
				<weight>1.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Waterskin</name>
				<weight>5.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Rope, hempen (50 feet)</name>
				<weight>10.0</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<container>
			<name>Money</name>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Copper (cp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.01</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Silver (sp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.1</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Electrum (ep)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.2</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Gold (gp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>15</quantity>
				<value>1.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Platinum (pp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>10.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<note>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Common, Orc</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Half-Orc</name>
			<text>Orc and human tribes sometimes form alliances, joining forces into a larger horde to the terror of civilized lands nearby. When these alliances are sealed by marriages, half-orcs are born. Some half-orcs rise to become proud chiefs of orc tribes, their human blood giving them an edge over their full-blooded ore rivals. Some venture into the world to prove their worth among humans and other more civilized races. Many of these become adventurers, achieving greatness for their mighty deeds and notoriety for their barbaric customs and savage fury.</text>
			<text>	Half-orcs' grayish pigmentation, sloping foreheads, jutting jaws, prominent teeth, and towering builds make their orcish heritage plain for all to see. Orcs regard battle scars as tokens of pride and ornamental scars as things of beauty.</text>
			<text>	Half-orcs feel emotion powerfully. Rage doesn't just quicken their pulse, it makes their bodies burn. An insult stings like acid, and sadness saps their strength. But they laugh loudly and heartily, and simple bodily pleasures-feasting, drinking, wrestling, drumming, and wild dancing-fill their hearts with joy. They tend to be short-tempered and sometimes sullen, more inclined to action than contemplation and to fighting than arguing. The most accomplished half-ores are those with enough self-control to get by in a civilized land.</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Rogue</name>
			<text>Rogues rely on skill, stealth, and their foes' vulnerabilities to get the upper hand in any situation. They have a knack for finding the solution to just about any problem.</text>
		</note>
		<abilities>8,15,13,13,10,14,</abilities>
		<hpMax>10</hpMax>
		<hpCurrent>10</hpCurrent>
	</character>
</pc>