<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<compendium version="5">
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Acolyte</name>
		<proficiency>Insight, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Insight, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A holy symbol (a gift to you when you entered the priesthood), a prayer book or prayer wheel, 5 sticks of incense, vestments, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Shelter of the Faithful</name>
			<text>As an acolyte, you command the respect of those who share your faith, and you can perform the religious ceremonies of your deity. You and your adventuring companions can expect to receive free healing and care at a temple, shrine, or other established presence of your faith, though you must provide any material components needed for spells. Those who share your religion will support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle.</text>
			<text />
			<text>You might also have ties to a specific temple dedicated to your chosen deity or pantheon, and you have a residence there. This could be the temple where you used to serve, if you remain on good terms with it, or a temple where you have found a new home. While near your temple, you can call upon the priests for assistance, provided the assistance you ask for is not hazardous and you remain in good standing with your temple.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Religious Community</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You're tightly connected with the religious community of Baldur's Gate. You know if a deity has a following in the city and any places that faith openly congregates and the neighborhoods those faithful typically inhabit. While this isn't remarkable for most of the city's larger faiths, keeping track of the hundreds of religions newcomers bring with them is no mean feat.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Charlatan</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Sleight of Hand</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Disguise Kit, Forgery Kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of fine clothes, a disguise kit, tools of the con of your choice (ten stoppered bottles filled with colored liquid, a set of weighted dice, a deck of marked cards, or a signet ring of an imaginary duke), and a belt pouch containing 15 gp.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: False Identity</name>
			<text>You have created a second identity that includes documentation, established acquaintances, and disguises that allow you to assume that persona. Additionally, you can forge documents including official papers and personal letters, as long as you have seen an example of the kind of document or the handwriting you are trying to copy.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Long-Lost Heir</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You're well-versed in the mannerisms and idiosyncrasies of Baldurian patriars and other nobles, imitating them smoothly enough to convince even the snootiest family heads of your authenticity. You're skilled at posing as the long-lost heir to some imaginary or extinguished patriar lineage.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>Because of your skill in passing yourself off as a patriar, you have a Watch token that allows you alone into the Upper City of Baldur's Gate. You might be able to bluff others through with you, or even convince members of the Watch that you're a patriar. However, any true test of your authenticity is likely to reveal your deception.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Criminal</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Stealth</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Stealth</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set, thieves' tools</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A crowbar, a set of dark common clothes including a hood, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Criminal Contact</name>
			<text>You have a reliable and trustworthy contact who acts as your liaison to a network of other criminals. You know how to get messages to and from your contact, even over great distances; specifically, you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Criminal Connections</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>In Baldur's Gate, crime is just another business. As a result, you can arrange a meeting with a low-ranking operative of nearly any business, patriar family, crew, government institution, or—certainly—the Guild. This operative will hear you out and, at their discretion, take your information or request up their chain of command. These meetings almost always occur in shady venues.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Entertainer</name>
		<proficiency>Acrobatics, Performance</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Acrobatics, Performance</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Disguise kit, one type of musical instrument</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A musical instrument (one of your choice), the favor of an admirer (love letter, lock of hair, or trinket), a costume, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: By Popular Demand</name>
			<text>You can always find a place to perform, usually in an inn or tavern but possibly with a circus, at a theater, or even in a noble's court. At such a place, you receive free lodging and food of a modest or comfortable standard (depending on the quality of the establishment), as long as you perform each night. In addition, your performance makes you something of a local figure. When strangers recognize you in a town where you have performed, they typically take a liking to you.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Backstage Pass</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You've learned that most of the real business of entertainment (or any other venture) happens behind the scenes. It's easy for you to case what sorts of audiences attend what venue—like how toughs gather at the Blushing Mermaid or how brash patriars congregate at the Helm and Cloak. After a successful performance, you may meet an enthusiastic member of the crowd—someone of an occupation or social class that frequents the establishment. This contact is delighted to talk with you, and to listen.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Folk Hero</name>
		<proficiency>Animal Handling, Survival</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Animal Handling, Survival</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of artisan's tools, vehicles (land)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), a shovel, an iron pot, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Rustic Hospitality</name>
			<text>Since you come from the ranks of the common folk, you fit in among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Social Vengeance</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You've lived your entire life in the Lower or Outer City of Baldur's Gate. You grew up seeing arrogant patriars flaunt their wealth while your hardworking neighbors struggled. As a result, you know how eager commoners in Baldur's Gate are to see any patriar get what they deserve. While in a busy part of the Lower City or Outer City of Baldur's Gate, you can spend 2d10 minutes to convince 1d6 commoners to perform a non-illegal act that inconveniences a member of the Watch or Flaming Fist, a patriar, or some other wealthy looking individual.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Guild Artisan</name>
		<proficiency>Insight, Persuasion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Insight, Persuasion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of artisan's tools</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), a letter of introduction from your guild, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Guild Membership</name>
			<text>As an established and respected member of a guild, you can rely on certain benefits that membership provides. Your fellow guild members will provide you with lodging and food if necessary, and pay for your funeral if needed. In some cities and towns, a guildhall offers a central place to meet other members of your profession, which can be a good place to meet potential patrons, allies, or hirelings.</text>
			<text />
			<text>Guilds often wield tremendous political power. If you are accused of a crime, your guild will support you if a good case can be made for your innocence or the crime is justifiable. You can also gain access to powerful political figures through the guild, if you are a member in good standing. Such connections might require the donation of money or magic items to the guild's coffers.</text>
			<text />
			<text>You must pay dues of 5 gp per month to the guild. If you miss payments, you must make up back dues to remain in the guild's good graces.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Professional Courtesy</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You're familiar with the city's crews, their territories, and inter-crew politics. Choose one of the three districts of Baldur's Gate: the Upper City, the Lower City, or the Outer City. This is the district where you conduct most of your business. Whenever you need information about something in one of that district's neighborhoods, you can seek out crew members in that area and learn the local gossip. You can also gain unimpeded entry to nearly any bank, guild hall, place of business, workhouse, or crew meeting place in your district.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Hermit</name>
		<proficiency>Medicine, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Medicine, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Herbalism Kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A scroll case stuffed full of notes from your studies or prayers, a winter blanket, a set of common clothes, an herbalism kit, and 5 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Discovery</name>
			<text>The quiet seclusion of your extended hermitage gave you access to a unique and powerful discovery. The exact nature of this revelation depends on the nature of your seclusion. It might be a great truth about the cosmos, the deities, the powerful beings of the outer planes, or the forces of nature. It could be a site that no one else has ever seen. You might have uncovered a fact that has long been forgotten, or unearthed some relic of the past that could rewrite history. It might be information that would be damaging to the people who or consigned you to exile, and hence the reason for your return to society.</text>
			<text />
			<text>Work with your DM to determine the details of your discovery and its impact on the campaign.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: The Real City</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You know the Baldur's Gate most Baldurians ignore, the dog-eat-dog world of the homeless and unfortunate. You know where to go in the Lower City and Outer City for anonymity. In these slums and alley camps, you can get a damp bed and a bad meal, but also a degree of privacy and no questions asked. Living here isn't comfortable, but it's unlikely anyone will find you—and you can stay as long as you want.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Noble</name>
		<proficiency>History, Persuasion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>History, Persuasion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of fine clothes, a signet ring, a scroll of pedigree, and a purse containing 25 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Position of Privilege</name>
			<text>Thanks to your noble birth, people are inclined to think the best of you. You are welcome in high society, and people assume you have the right to be wherever you are. The common folk make every effort to accommodate you and avoid your displeasure, and other people of high birth treat you as a member of the same social sphere. You can secure an audience with a local noble if you need to.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Patriar</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>As a member of one of the elite families of Baldur's Gate, you may pass through city gates without paying tolls, mingle among the Gate's nobility unquestioned, and impress those on the lookout for wealthy patrons. You are welcome in the Upper City and may stay there after dark without being harassed or evicted. Your word is accepted over others' without question, and any corruption among guards or government officials tends to work in your favor, not against you—at least until you make some effort to expose it.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Outlander</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Survival</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, Survival</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of musical instrument</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A staff, a hunting trap, a trophy from an animal you killed, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Wanderer</name>
			<text>You have an excellent memory for maps and geography, and you can always recall the general layout of terrain, settlements, and other features around you. In addition, you can find food and fresh water for yourself and up to five other people each day, provided that the land offers berries, small game, water, and so forth.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Immigrant Experience</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>Even after your short time in Baldur's Gate, you've learned the city holds more walls and gates than those the Watch and Flaming Fist patrols. You are known within the city's immigrant communities. Should you ever need to learn about a foreign land, people, tradition, or history, you know where to find someone with firsthand experience—likely somewhere in the Outer City.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Sage</name>
		<proficiency>Arcana, History</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Arcana, History</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A bottle of black ink, a quill, a small knife, a letter from a dead colleague posing a question you have not yet been able to answer, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Researcher</name>
			<text>When you attempt to learn or recall a piece of lore, if you do not know that information, you often know where and from whom you can obtain it. Usually, this information comes from a library, scriptorium, university, or a sage or other learned person or creature, Your DM might rule that the knowledge you seek is secreted away in an almost inaccessible place, or that it simply cannot be found. Unearthing the deepest secrets of the multiverse can require an adventure or even a whole campaign.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Rumor Monger</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>Via your personal rumor mill and articles published in Baldur's Mouth, you can surmise a great deal about Baldurians' secrets—who's practicing necromancy, who's involved in spying or smuggling, who would purchase or craft dangerous magical wares without batting an eyelash. Whenever a noteworthy crime or mysterious happening occurs in the city, you immediately have a list of 1d4 suspects who, if they aren't involved, have a strong chance of knowing who is.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Sailor</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, Perception</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Navigator's tools, vehicles(water)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A belaying pin (dub), 50 feet of silk rope, a lucky charm such as a rabbit foot or a small stone with a hole in the center (or you may roll for a random trinket on the Trinkets table in chapter 5), a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Ship's Passage</name>
			<text>When you need to, you can secure free passage on a sailing ship for yourself and your adventuring companions. You might sail on the ship you served on, or another ship you have good relations with (perhaps one captained by a former crewmate). Because you're calling in a favor, you can't be certain of a schedule or route that will meet your every need. Your Dungeon Master will determine how long it takes to get where you need to go. In return for your free passage, you and your companions are expected to assist the crew during the voyage.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Smuggler's Sense</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You're familiar with the docks of Baldur's Gate, the movement of inspectors and tax collectors, the way cargo and coin flows. As a result, it's easy for you to hustle a load of cargo ashore or see such a cargo onto a cooperative ship without attracting suspicion or taxation. You also know the movements of the Gray Wavers—the Flaming Fist harbor guards—and have a sense of how to operate the city's mechanized cranes.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Soldier</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, Intimidation</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set, vehicles (land)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>An insignia of rank, a trophy taken from a fallen enemy (a dagger, broken blade, or piece of a banner), a set of bone dice or deck of cards, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Military Rank</name>
			<text>You have a military rank from your career as a soldier. Soldiers loyal to your former military organization still recognize your authority and influence, and they defer to you if they are of a lower rank. You can invoke your rank to exert influence over other soldiers and requisition simple equipment or horses for temporary use. You can also usually gain access to friendly military encampments and fortresses where your rank is recognized.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: City Guard</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>You may choose to currently serve in either the Flaming Fist or the Watch. If you do, you have responsibilities related to your post. For as long as you perform these responsibilities, you gain benefits. If you stop performing your responsibilities, though, you lose access to the benefits and might suffer further fallout. Should you lose these benefits, you may regain them by having an unpleasant conversation with your commanding officer and fulfilling your responsibilities for a month.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>	Flaming Fist. If you serve in the Flaming Fist, once every ten days, you must report to the Seatower of Balduran for training, and you're required to take a regular shift patrolling either the Lower City or the Outer City. In return, you have access to the Flaming Fist's fortresses and a direct line of communication with Flaming Fist officers and other soldiers. You can also pass through the city's gates without question—although you can't bring guests into the Upper City as a member of the Watch might. Additionally, you're always welcome at the Three Old Kegs, where the Three Old Toads are glad to greet you with a smile and a mug of ale.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>	The Watch. If you serve in the Watch, you're required to conduct a regular patrol in the Upper City or take a regular shift at its gates, and must report for training in the Watch Citadel once every ten days. In return, you have access to the Citadel and a direct line of communication with Watch officers and officials. Your word carries considerable weight in the High Hall, and most establishments in the Citadel Streets neighborhood are happy to give you and your friends free meals. Additionally, you can escort people into the Upper City without question, regardless of whether they are patriars or have Watch tokens. Outside the Upper City, however, most people regard you with suspicion, and you generally get a chilly reception while in uniform.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Baldur's Gate Urchin</name>
		<proficiency>Sleight of Hand, Stealth</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Sleight of Hand, Stealth</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Disguise Kit, thieves' tools</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A small knife, a map of the city you grew up in, a pet mouse, a token to remember your parents by, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: City Secrets</name>
			<text>You know the secret patterns and flow to cities and can find passages through the urban sprawl that others would miss. When you are not in combat, you (and companions you lead) can travel between any two locations in the city twice as fast as your speed would normally allow.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Baldur's Gate Feature: Gateguide Connection</name>
			<text>The effects of a Baldur's Gate feature can be used only while the character is in Baldur's Gate—though, at the DM's discretion, they might have applicable effects in situations similar to those in Baldur's Gate.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>Even though you might not be a member of the Gateguides crew, you've associated with enough of them that you know their torch-based code. From the lighting, placement, and type of torch arranged on or near a structure, you can gather a great deal of information about those who live or do business there, particularly if they deal fairly with strangers, have Guild or government connections, or have either helped or denied the Gateguides in the past.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Faceless</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Intimidation</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Disguise kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>Disguise kit, a costume, a pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Faceless Persona</name>
			<text>A faceless character adventures behind the mask of a public persona. This persona is as natural to them as their hidden, true face, but it disguises their identity. Roll on the Faceless Persona table to determine your persona, or work with the DM to create a persona that's unique to your character and suits the tone of your game.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>d10   Faceless Persona</text>
			<text>1     A flamboyant spy or brigand</text>
			<text>2     The incarnation of a nation or people</text>
			<text>3     A scoundrel with a masked guise</text>
			<text>4     A vengeful spirit</text>
			<text>5     The manifestation of a deity or your faith</text>
			<text>6     One whose beauty is greatly accented using makeup</text>
			<text>7     An impersonation of another hero</text>
			<text>8     The embodiment of a school of magic</text>
			<text>9     A warrior with distinctive armor</text>
			<text>10    A disguise with animalistic or monstrous characteristics, meant to inspire fear</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Dual Personalities</name>
			<text>Most of your fellow adventurers and the world know you as your persona. Those who seek to learn more about you—your weaknesses, your origins, your purpose—find themselves stymied by your disguise. Upon donning a disguise and behaving as your persona, you are unidentifiable as your true self. By removing your disguise and revealing your true face, you are no longer identifiable as your persona. This allows you to change appearances between your two personalities as often as you wish, using one to hide the other or serve as convenient camouflage. However, should someone realize the connection between your persona and your true self, your deception might lose its effectiveness.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
</compendium>