<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<background>
		<name>Augen Trust (Spy)</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Stealth</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Stealth</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set, thieves' tools</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A crowbar, a set of dark common clothes including a hood, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Spy Contact</name>
			<text>You have a reliable and trustworthy contact who acts as your liaison to a network of other spies. You know how to get messages to and from your contact, even over great distances; specifically, you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Cobalt Scholar (Sage)</name>
		<proficiency>Arcana, History</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Arcana, History</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A bottle of black ink, a quill, a small knife, a letter from a dead colleague posing a question you have not yet been able to answer, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Researcher</name>
			<text>When you attempt to learn or recall a piece of lore, if you do not know that information, you often know where and from whom you can obtain it. Usually, this information comes from a library, scriptorium, university, or a sage or other learned person or creature, Your DM might rule that the knowledge you seek is secreted away in an almost inaccessible place, or that it simply cannot be found. Unearthing the deepest secrets of the multiverse can require an adventure or even a whole campaign.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Luxonborn (Acolyte)</name>
		<proficiency>Insight, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Insight, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A holy symbol (a gift to you when you entered the priesthood), a prayer book or prayer wheel, 5 sticks of incense, vestments, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Shelter of the Faithful</name>
			<text>As an acolyte, you command the respect of those who share your faith, and you can perform the religious ceremonies of your deity. You and your adventuring companions can expect to receive free healing and care at a temple, shrine, or other established presence of your faith, though you must provide any material components needed for spells. Those who share your religion will support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>You might also have ties to a specific temple dedicated to your chosen deity or pantheon, and you have a residence there. This could be the temple where you used to serve, if you remain on good terms with it, or a temple where you have found a new home. While near your temple, you can call upon the priests for assistance, provided the assistance you ask for is not hazardous and you remain in good standing with your temple.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Myriad Operative (Criminal)</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Stealth</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Stealth</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set, thieves' tools</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A crowbar, a set of dark common clothes including a hood, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Criminal Contact</name>
			<text>You have a reliable and trustworthy contact who acts as your liaison to a network of other criminals. You know how to get messages to and from your contact, even over great distances; specifically, you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Revelry Pirate (Sailor)</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, Perception</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Navigator's tools, vehicles(water)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A belaying pin (dub), 50 feet of silk rope, a lucky charm such as a rabbit foot or a small stone with a hole in the center (or you may roll for a random trinket on the Trinkets table in chapter 5), a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Ship's Passage</name>
			<text>When you need to, you can secure free passage on a sailing ship for yourself and your adventuring companions. You might sail on the ship you served on, or another ship you have good relations with (perhaps one captained by a former crewmate). Because you're calling in a favor, you can't be certain of a schedule or route that will meet your every need. Your Dungeon Master will determine how long it takes to get where you need to go. In return for your free passage, you and your companions are expected to assist the crew during the voyage.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Grinner</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Performance</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Performance</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of musical instrument, thieves' tools</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of fine clothes, a disguise kit, a musical instrument of your choice, a gold-plated ring depicting a smiling face, and a pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Ballad of the Grinning Fool</name>
			<text>Like every Grinner, you know how to find a hideout. In any city of 10,000 people or more on the Menagerie Coast or in the lands of the Dwendalian Empire, you can play the "Ballad of the Grinning Fool" in a major tavern or inn. A member of the Golden Grin will find you and give shelter to you and any companions you vouch for. This shelter might be discontinued if it becomes too dangerous to hide you, at the DM's discretion.</text>
			<text>	This feature must be used with caution, for not all who know the ballad are your friends. Some are traitors, counterspies, or agents of tyranny.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Volstrucker Agent</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Stealth</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Stealth</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Poisoner's kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of common clothes, a black cloak with a hood, a poisoner's kit, and a pouch containing 10 gpA set of common clothes, a black cloak with a hood, a poisoner's kit, and a pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Shadow Network</name>
			<text>You have access to the Volstrucker shadow network, which allows you to communicate with other members of the order over long distances. If you write a letter in a special arcane ink, address it to a member of the Volstrucker, and cast it into a fire, the letter will burn to cinders and materialize whole again on the person of the agent you addressed it to.</text>
			<text>	The ink used to send a letter across the shadow network is the same as that used by a wizard to scribe spells in a spellbook. Writing a letter in this ink costs 10 gp per pag</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
</compendium>
