<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
    <!-- Not new spells, just a limited list what is in the provided rulebook to avoid confusion -->
    <spell>
        <name>Aid</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a tiny strip of white cloth)</components>
        <duration>8 hours</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Paladin</classes>
        <text>Your spell bolsters your allies with toughness and resolve. Choose up to three creatures within range. Each target's hit point maximum and current hit points increase by 5 for the duration.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, a target's hit points increase by an additional 5 for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Augury</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>D</school>
        <ritual>YES</ritual>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <components>V, S, M (specially marked sticks, bones, or similar tokens worth at least 25 gp)</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>By casting gem-inlaid sticks, rolling dragon bones, laying out ornate cards, or employing some other divining tool, you receive an omen from an otherworldly entity about the results of a specific course of action that you plan to take within the next 30 minutes. The DM chooses from the following possible omens.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• Weal, for good results</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• Woe, for bad results</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• Weal and woe, for both good and bad results</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• Nothing, for results that aren't especially good or bad</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The spell doesn't take into account any possible circumstances that might change the outcome, such as the casting of additional spells or the loss or gain of a companion.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If you cast the spell two or more times before completing your next long rest, there is a cumulative 25 percent chance for each casting after the first that you get a random reading. The DM makes this roll in secret.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Beacon of Hope</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>This spell bestows hope and vitality. Choose any number of creatures within range. For the duration, each target has advantage on Wisdom saving throws and death saving throws, and regains the maximum number of hit points possible from any healing.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Bless</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a sprinkling of holy water)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Paladin</classes>
        <text>You bless up to three creatures of your choice within range. Whenever a target makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Blur</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>I</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>Your body becomes blurred, shifting and wavering to all who can see you. For the duration, any creature has disadvantage on attack rolls against you. An attacker is immune to this effect if it doesn't rely on sight, as with blindsight, or can see through illusions, as with truesight.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Burning Hands</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot cone)</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>As you hold your hands with thumbs touching and fingers spread, a thin sheet of flames shoots forth from your outstretched fingertips. Each creature in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>3d6</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Charm Person</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You attempt to charm a humanoid you can see within range. It must make a Wisdom saving throw, and does so with advantage if you or your companions are fighting it. If it fails the saving throw, it is charmed by you until the spell ends or until you or your companions do anything harmful to it. The charmed creature regards you as a friendly acquaintance. When the spell ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Command</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Paladin</classes>
        <text>You speak a one-word command to a creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or follow the command on its next turn. The spell has no effect if the target is undead, if it doesn't understand your language, or if your command is directly harmful to it.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Some typical commands and their effects follow. You might issue a command other than one described here. If you do so, the DM determines how the target behaves. If the target can't follow your command, the spell ends.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Approach: The target moves toward you by the shortest and most direct route, ending its turn if it moves within 5 feet of you.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Drop: The target drops whatever it is holding and then ends its turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Flee: The target spends its turn moving away from you by the fastest available means.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Grovel: The target falls prone and then ends its turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Halt: The target doesn't move and takes no actions. A flying creature stays aloft, provided that it is able to do so. If it must move to stay aloft, it flies the minimum distance needed to remain in the air.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Comprehend Languages</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>D</school>
        <ritual>YES</ritual>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a pinch of soot and salt)</components>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>For the duration, you understand the literal meaning of any spoken language that you hear. You also understand any spoken language that you hear. You also understand any written language that you see, but you must be touching the surface of which the words are written. It takes about 1 minute to read one page of text.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>This spell doesn't decode secret messages in a text or glyph, such as an arcane sigil, that isn't part of a written language.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Cure Wounds</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Paladin, Ranger</classes>
        <text>A creature you touch regains a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>1d8+SPELL</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Dancing Lights</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You create up to four torch-sized lights within range, making them appear as torches, lanterns, or glowing orbs that hover in the air for the duration. You can also combine the four lights into one glowing vaguely humanoid form of Medium size. Whichever form you choose, each light sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the lights up to 60 feet to a new spot within range. A light must be within 20 feet of another light created by this spell, and a light winks out if it exceeds the spell's range.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Darkness</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, M (bat fur and a drop of pitch or piece of coal)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>Magical darkness spreads from a point you choose within range to fill a 15-foot radius sphere for the duration. The darkness spreads around corners. A creature with darkvision can't see through this darkness, and nonmagical light can't illuminate it.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If the point you choose is on an object you are holding or one that isn't being worn or carried, the darkness emanates from the object and moves with it. Completely covering the source of the darkness with an opaque object, such as a bowl or a helm, blocks the darkness.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If any of this spell's area overlaps with an area of light created by a spell of 2nd level or lower, the spell that created the light is dispelled.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Detect Magic</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>D</school>
        <ritual>YES</ritual>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Paladin, Ranger, Wizard</classes>
        <text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Dispel Magic</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Paladin, Wizard</classes>
        <text>Choose any creature, object, or magical effect within range. Any spell of 3rd level or lower on the target ends. For each spell of 4th level or higher on the target, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell's level. On a successful check, the spell ends.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you automatically end the effects of a spell on the target if the spell's level is equal to or less than the level of the spell slot you used.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Fear</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>I</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (30-foot cone)</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a white feather or the heart of a hen)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You project a phantasmal image of a creature's worst fears. Each creature in a 30-foot cone must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or drop whatever it is holding and become frightened for the duration.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>While frightened by this spell, a creature must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest available route on each of its turns, unless there is nowhere to move. If the creature ends its turn in a location where it doesn't have line of sight to you, the creature can make a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends for that creature.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Feather Fall</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 reaction, which you take when you or a creature within 60 feet of you falls</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, M (a white feather or the heart of a hen)</components>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>Reaction - When you or a creature within 60 feet of you falls Choose up to five falling creatures within range. A falling creature's rate of descent slows to 60 feet per round until the spell ends. If the creature lands before the spell ends, it takes no falling damage and can land on its feet, and the spell ends for that creature.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Fireball</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a tiny ball of bat guano and sulfur)</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>A bright streak flashes from your pointing finger to a point you choose within range then blossoms with a low roar into an explosion of flame. Each creature in a 20-foot radius must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Flaming Sphere</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>C</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a bit of tallow, a pinch of brimstone, and a dusting of powdered iron)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>A 5-foot-diameter sphere of fire appears in an unoccupied space of your choice within range and lasts for the duration. Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of the sphere must make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>As a bonus action, you can move the sphere up to 30 feet. If you ram the sphere into a creature, that creature must make the saving throw against the sphere's damage, and the sphere stops moving this turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>When you move the sphere, you can direct it over barriers up to 5 feet tall and jump it across pits up to 10 feet wide. The sphere ignites flammable objects not being worn or carried, and it sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
        <roll>2d6</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Fly</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a wing feather from any bird)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>You touch a willing creature. The target gains a flying speed of 60 feet for the duration. When the spell ends, the target falls if it is still aloft, unless it can stop the fall.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 3rd.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Guidance</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>D</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>You touch one willing creature. Once before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to one ability check of its choice. It can roll the die before or after making the ability check. The spell then ends.</text>
        <roll>1d4</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Guiding Bolt</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>A flash of light streaks toward a creature of your choice within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 4d6 radiant damage, and the next attack roll made against this target before the end of your next turn has advantage, thanks to the mystical dim light glittering on the target until then.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>1d20+SPELL+PROF</roll>
        <roll>4d6</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Healing Word</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric</classes>
        <text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>1d4+SPELL</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Hold Person</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a small, straight piece of iron)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Wizard</classes>
        <text>Choose a humanoid that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target on additional humanoid for each slot level above 2nd. The humanoids must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Hunter's Mark</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>D</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Ranger</classes>
        <text>You choose a creature you can see within range and mystically mark it as your quarry. Until the spell ends, you deal an extra 1d6 damage to the target whenever you hit it with a weapon attack, and you have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Wisdom (Survival) check you make to find it. If the target drops to 0 hit points before this spell ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to mark a new creature.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd or 4th level, you can maintain your concentration on the spell for up to 8 hours. When you use a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can maintain your concentration on the spell for up to 24 hours.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Identify</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>D</school>
        <ritual>YES</ritual>
        <time>1 minute</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a pearl worth at least 100 gp and an owl feather)</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You choose one object that you must touch throughout the casting of the spell. If it is a magic item or some other magic-imbued object, you learn its properties and how to use them, whether it requires attunement to use, and how many charges it has, if any. You learn whether any spells are affecting the item and what they are. If the item was created by a spell, you learn which spell created it.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If you instead touch a creature throughout the casting, you learn what spells, if any, are currently affecting it.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Inflict Wounds</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>N</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>Make a melee spell attack against a creature you can reach. On a hit, the target takes 3d10 necrotic damage.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>1d20+SPELL+PROF</roll>
        <roll>3d10</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Invisibility</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>I</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (an eyelash encased in gum arabic)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>A creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target's person. The spell ends for a target that attacks or casts a spell.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Lesser Restoration</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Paladin, Ranger</classes>
        <text>You touch a creature and can end either one disease or one condition afflicting it. The condition can be blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Light</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, M (a firefly or phosphorescent moss)</components>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You touch one object that is no larger than 10 feet in any dimension. Until the spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. Completely covering the object with something opaque blocks the light. The spell ends if you cast it again or dismiss it as an action.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If you target an object held or worn by a hostile creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Lightning Bolt</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (100-foot line)</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a bit of fur and a rod of amber, crystal, or glass)</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>A stroke of lightning forming a line of 100 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 8d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The lightning ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot above 3rd.</text>
        <roll>8d6</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Longstrider</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a pinch of dirt)</components>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <classes>BardRanger, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You touch a creature. The target's speed increases by 10 feet until the spell ends.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Mage Armor</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a piece of cured leather)</components>
        <duration>8 hours</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>You touch a willing creature who isn't wearing armor, and a protective magical force surrounds it until the spell ends. The target's base AC becomes 13 + its Dexterity modifier. The spell ends it if the target dons armor or if you dismiss the spell as an action.</text>
        <roll>13+DEX</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Mage Hand</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>C</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>A spectral, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand lasts for the duration or until you dismiss it as an action. The hand vanishes if it is ever more than 30 feet away from you or if you cast this spell again.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>You can use your action to control the hand. You can use the hand to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you use it.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The hand can't attack, activate magical items, or carry more than 10 pounds.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Magic Missile</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>You create three glowing darts of magical force. Each dart hits a creature of your choice that you can see within range. A dart deals 1d4+1 force damage to its target. The darts all strike simultaneously and you can direct them to hit one creature or several.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell creates one more dart for each slot above 1st.</text>
        <roll>1d4+1</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Magic Weapon</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Paladin, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You touch a nonmagical weapon. Until the spell ends, that weapon becomes a magic weapon with a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the bonus increases to +2. When you use a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the bonus increases to +3.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Mass Healing Word</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>As you call out words of restoration, up to six creatures of your choice that you can see within range regain hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 3rd.</text>
        <roll>1d4+SPELL</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Misty Step</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>C</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>Briefly surrounded by silvery mist, you teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Prayer of Healing</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>10 minutes</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>Up to six creatures of your choice that you can see within range each regain hit points equal to 2d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
        <roll>2d8+SPELL</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Prestidigitation</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>10 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>This spell is a minor magical trick that novice spellcasters use for practice. You create one of the following magical effects within range.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, faint musical notes, or an odd odor.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You instantaneously light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You instantaneously clean or soil an object no larger than 1 cubic foot.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You chill, warm, or flavor up to 1 cubic foot of nonliving material for 1 hour.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You make a color, a small mark, or a symbol appear on an object or a surface for 1 hour.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You create a nonmagical trinket or an illusory image that can fit in your hand and that lasts until the end of your next turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its non-instantaneous effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Protection from Energy</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Ranger, Wizard</classes>
        <text>For the duration, the willing creature you touch has resistance to one damage type of your choice - acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Protection from Evil and Good</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (holy water or powdered silver and iron, which the spell consumes)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Paladin, Wizard</classes>
        <text>Until the spell ends, one willing creature you touch is protected against certain types of creatures - aberrations, celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The protection grants several benefits. Creatures of those types have disadvantage on attack rolls against the target. The target also can't be charmed, frightened, or possessed by them. If the target is already charmed, frightened, or possessed by such a creature, the target has advantage on any new saving throw against the relevant effect.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Ray of Frost</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>A frigid beam of blue-white light streaks toward a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, it takes 1d8 cold damage, and its speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</text>
        <roll>1d20+SPELL+PROF</roll>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Resistance</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>You touch one willing creature. Once before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to one saving throw of its choice. It can roll the die before or after the saving throw. The spell then ends.</text>
        <roll>d4</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Revivify</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>N</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (diamonds worth 300 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Paladin</classes>
        <text>You touch a creature that has died within the last minute. That creature returns to life with 1 hit point. This spell can't return to life a creature that has died of old age, nor can it restore any missing body parts.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sacred Flame</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>Flame-like radiance descends on a creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 radiant damage. The target gains no benefit from cover for this saving throw.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</text>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sanctuary</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a small silver mirror)</components>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>You ward a creature within range against attack. Until the spell ends, any creature who targets the warded creature with an attack or a harmful spell must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. This spell doesn't protect the warded creature from area effects, such as the explosion of a fireball.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If the warded creature makes an attack or casts a spell that affects an enemy creature, this spell ends.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sending</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Unlimited</range>
        <components>V, S, M (A short piece of fine copper wire)</components>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You send a short message of twenty-five words or less to a creature with you are familiar. The creature hears the message in its mind, recognizes you as the sender if it knows you, and can answer in a like manner immediately. The spell enables creatures with Intelligence scores of at least 1 to understand the meaning of your message.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>You can send the message across any distance and even to other planes of existence, but if the target is on a different plane than you, there is a 5 percent chance that the message doesn't arrive.</text>
        <roll>1d20</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Shield</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>1 round</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Shield of Faith</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a small parchment with a bit of holy text written on it)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Cleric, Paladin</classes>
        <text>A shimmering field appears and surrounds a creature of your choice within range, granting it a +2 bonus to AC for the duration.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Shocking Grasp</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>Lightning springs from your hand to deliver a shock to a creature you try to touch. Make a melee spell attack against the target. You have advantage on the attack roll if the target is wearing armor made of metal. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 lightning damage, and it can't take reactions until the start of its next turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</text>
        <roll>1d20+SPELL+PROF</roll>
        <roll>1d8</roll>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
        <roll>4d8</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Silence</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>I</school>
        <ritual>YES</ritual>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Ranger</classes>
        <text>For the duration, no sound can be created within or pass through a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range. Any creature or object entirely inside the sphere is immune to thunder damage, and creatures are deafened while entirely inside it. Casting a spell that includes a verbal component is impossible there.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sleep</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>90 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a pinch of find sand, rose petals, or a cricket)</components>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>This spell sends creatures into a magical slumber. Roll 5d8, the total is how many hit points of creatures this spell can affect. Creatures within 20 feet of a point you choose within range are affected in ascending order of their current hit points (ignoring unconscious creatures).</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Starting with the creature that has the lowest current hit points, each creature affected by this spell falls unconscious until the spell ends, the sleeper takes damage, or someone uses an action to shake or slap the sleeper awake. Subtract each creature's hit points from the total before moving on to the creature with the next lowest hit points. A creature's hit points must be equal to or less than the remaining total for that creature to be affected.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Undead and creatures immune to being charmed aren't affected by this spell.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, roll an additional 2d8 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>5d8</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Speak with Dead</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>N</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>10 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (burning incense)</components>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric</classes>
        <text>You grant the semblance of life and intelligence to a corpse of your choice within range, allowing it to answer the questions you pose. The corpse must still have a mouth and can't be undead. The spell fails if the corpse was the target of this spell within the last 10 days.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Until the spell ends, you can ask the corpse up to five questions. The corpse knows only what it knew in life, including the languages it knew. Answers are usually brief, cryptic, or repetitive, and the corpse is under no compulsion to offer a truthful answer if you are hostile to it or it recognizes you as an enemy. This spell doesn't return the creature's soul to its body, only its animating spirit. Thus, the corpse can't learn new information, doesn't comprehend anything that has happened since it died, and can't speculate about future events.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Spirit Guardians</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>C</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot-radius)</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a holy symbol)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>You call forth spirits to protect you. They flit around you to a distance of 15 feet for the duration. If you are good or neutral, their spectral form appears angelic or fey (your choice). If you are evil, they appear fiendish.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>When you cast this spell, you can designate any number of creatures you can see to be unaffected by it. An affected creature's speed is halved in the area, and when the creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d8 radiant damage (if you are good or neutral) or 3d8 necrotic damage (if you are evil). On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 3rd.</text>
        <roll>3d8</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Spiritual Weapon</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 bonus action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>You create a floating, spectral weapon within range that lasts for the duration or until you cast this spell again. When you cast the spell, you can make a melee spell attack against a creature within 5 feet of the weapon. On a hit, the target takes force damage equal to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the weapon up to 20 feet and repeat the attack against a creature within 5 feet of it.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The weapon can take whatever form you choose. Clerics of deities who are associated with a particular weapon (as St. Cuthbert is known for his mace and Thor for his hammer) make this spell's effect resemble that weapon.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for every two slot levels above the 2nd.</text>
        <roll>1d20+SPELL+PROF</roll>
        <roll>1d8+SPELL</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Suggestion</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V, M (a snake's tongue and either a bit of honeycomb or a drop of sweet oil)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 8 hours</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>You suggest a course of activity (limited to a sentence or two) and magically influence a creature you can see within range that can hear and understand you. Creatures that can't be charmed are immune to this effect. The suggestion must be worded in such a manner as to make the course of action sound reasonable. Asking the creature to stab itself, throw itself onto a spear, immolate itself, or do some other obviously harmful act ends the spell.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it purses the course of action you described to the best of its ability. The suggested course of action can continue for the entire duration. If the suggested activity can be completed in a shorter time, the spell ends when the subject finishes what it was asked to do.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>You can also specify conditions that will trigger a special activity during the duration. For example, you might suggest that a knight give her warhorse to the first beggar she meets. If the condition isn't met before the spell expires, the activity isn't preformed.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If you or any of your companions damage the target, the spell ends.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Thaumaturgy</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>You manifest a minor wonder, a sign of supernatural power, within range. You create one of the following magical effects within range.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• Your voice booms up to three times as loud as normal for 1 minute.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You cause flames to flicker, brighten, dim, or change color for 1 minute.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You cause harmless tremors in the ground for 1 minute.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You create an instantaneous sound that originates from a point of your choice within range, such as a rumble of thunder, the cry of a raven, or ominous whispers.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You instantaneously cause an unlocked door or window to fly open or slam shut.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>• You alter the appearance of your eyes for 1 minute.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its 1-minute effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Thunderwave</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot cube)</range>
        <components>V, S</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Wizard</classes>
        <text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn't pushed.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>In addition, unsecured objects that are completely within the area of effect are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by the spell's effect, and the spell emits a thunderous boom audible out to 300 feet.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
        <roll>2d8</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Vicious Mockery</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Bard</classes>
        <text>You unleash a string of insults laced with subtle enchantments at a creature you can see within range. If the target can hear you (thought it need not understand you), it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 1d4 psychic damage and have disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>This spell's damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4) and 17th level (4d4).</text>
        <roll>1d4</roll>
        <roll>2d4</roll>
        <roll>3d4</roll>
        <roll>4d4</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Warding Bond</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a pair of platinum rings worth at least 50 gp each, which you and target must wear for the duration)</components>
        <duration>1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Cleric</classes>
        <text>This spell wards a willing creature you touch and creates a mystic connection between you and the target until the spell ends. While the target is within 60 feet of you, it gains a +1 bonus to AC and saving throws, and it has resistance to all damage. Also, each time it takes damage, you take the same amount of damage.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The spell ends if you drop to 0 hit points or if you and the target become separated by more than 60 feet. It also ends if the spell is cast again on either of the connected creatures. You can also dismiss the spell as an action.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Web</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>C</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M (a bit of spider web)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Wizard</classes>
        <text>You conjure a mass of thick, sticky webbing at a point of your choice within range. The webs fill a 20-foot cube from that point for the duration. The webs are difficult terrain and lightly obscure their area.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>If the webs aren't anchored between two solid masses (such as walls or trees) or layered across a floor, wall, or ceiling, the conjured web collapses on itself, and the spell ends at the start of your next turn. Webs layered over a flat surface have a depth of 5 feet.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>Each creature that starts its turn in the webs or that enters them during its turn must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is restrained as long as it remains in the webs or until it breaks free.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>A creature restrained by the webs can use its actions to make a Strength check against your spell save DC. If it succeeds, it is no longer restrained.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>The webs are flammable. Any 5-foot cube of webs exposed to fire burns away in 1 round, dealing 2d4 fire damage to any creature that starts its turn in the fire.</text>
        <roll>2d4</roll>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Zone of Truth</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EN</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>V, S, M</components>
        <duration>10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Bard, Cleric, Paladin</classes>
        <text>You create a magical zone that guards against deception in a 15-foot-radius sphere centered on a point of your choice within range. Until the spell ends, a creature that enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, a creature can't speak a deliberate lie while in the radius. You know whether each creature succeeds or fails on its saving throw.</text>
        <text/>
        <text>An affected creature is aware of the spell and can thus avoid answering questions to which it would normally respond with a lie. Such creatures can be evasive in its answers as long as it remains within the boundaries of the truth.</text>
    </spell>
</compendium>