<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Warlock">
		<name>Warlock (Genie)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Genie</name>
				<text>You have made a pact with one of the rarest kinds of genie, a noble genie. Such entities rule vast fiefs on the Elemental Planes and have great influence over lesser genies and elemental creatures. Noble genies are varied in their motivations, but most are arrogant and wield power that rivals that of lesser deities. They delight in turning the table on mortals, who often bind genies into servitude, and readily enter into pacts that expand their reach.</text>
				<text>	You choose your patron's kind or determine it randomly, using the Genie Kind table.</text>
				<text>	Genie Kind</text>
				<text>	d4    Kind       Element</text>
				<text>	1     Dao        Earth</text>
				<text>	2     Djinni     Air</text>
				<text>	3     Efreeti    Fire</text>
				<text>	4     Marid      Water</text>
				<text>	Expanded Spell List. 1st-level Genie feature,The Genie lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The Genie Expanded Spells table shows the genie spells that are added to the warlock spell list for you, along with the spells associated in the table with your patron's kind: dao, djinni, efreeti, or marid.</text>
				<text></text>
				<text>Genie Expanded Spells</text>
				<text>Spell Level    Genie Spells</text>
				<text>1st            detect evil and good</text>
				<text>2nd            phantasmal force</text>
				<text>3rd            create food and water</text>
				<text>4th            phantasmal killer</text>
				<text>5th            creation</text>
				<text>9th            wish</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Genie Expanded Spells:Dao</name>
				<text>Spell Level    Dao Spells</text>
				<text>1st            sanctuary</text>
				<text>2nd            spike growth</text>
				<text>3rd            meld into stone</text>
				<text>4th            stone shape</text>
				<text>5th            wall of stone</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Genie Expanded Spells:Djinni</name>
				<text>Spell Level    Djinni Spells</text>
				<text>1st            thunderwave</text>
				<text>2nd            gust of wind</text>
				<text>3rd            wind wall</text>
				<text>4th            greater invisibility</text>
				<text>5th            seeming</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Genie Expanded Spells:Efreeti</name>
				<text>Spell Level    Efreeti Spells</text>
				<text>1st            burning hands</text>
				<text>2nd            scorching ray</text>
				<text>3rd            fireball</text>
				<text>4th            fire shield</text>
				<text>5th            flame strike</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Genie Expanded Spells:Marid</name>
				<text>Spell Level    Marid Spells</text>
				<text>1st            fog cloud</text>
				<text>2nd            blur</text>
				<text>3rd            sleet storm</text>
				<text>4th            control water</text>
				<text>5th            cone of cold</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Genie: Genie's Vessel</name>
				<text>Your patron gifts you a magical vessel that grants you a measure of the genie's power. The vessel is a Tiny object, and you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells. You decide what the object is, or you can determine what it is randomly by rolling on the Genie's Vessel table.</text>
				<text>	Genie's Vessel</text>
				<text>	d6    Vessel</text>
				<text>	1     Oil lamp</text>
				<text>	2     Urn</text>
				<text>	3     Ring with a compartment</text>
				<text>	4     Stoppered bottle</text>
				<text>	5     Hollow statuette</text>
				<text>	6     Ornate lantern</text>
				<text>	While you are touching the vessel, you can use it in the following ways:</text>
				<text>	The vessel's AC equals your spell save DC. Its hit points equal your warlock level plus your proficiency bonus, and it is immune to poison and psychic damage.</text>
				<text>	If the vessel is destroyed or you lose it, you can perform a 1-hour ceremony to receive a replacement from your patron. This ceremony can be performed during a short or long rest, and the previous vessel is destroyed if it still exists. The vessel vanishes in a flare of elemental power when you die.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Genie: Bottled Respite</name>
				<text>As an action, you can magically vanish and enter your vessel, which remains in the space you left. The interior of the vessel is an extradimensional space in the shape of a 20-foot-radius cylinder, 20 feet high, and resembles your vessel. The interior is appointed with cushions and low tables and is a comfortable temperature. While inside, you can hear the area around your vessel as if you were in its space. You can remain inside the vessel up to a number of hours equal to twice your proficiency bonus. You exit the vessel early if you use a bonus action to leave, if you die, or if the vessel is destroyed. When you exit the vessel, you appear in the unoccupied space closest to it. Any objects left in the vessel remain there until carried out, and if the vessel is destroyed, every object stored there harmlessly appears in the unoccupied spaces closest to the vessel's former space. Once you enter the vessel, you can't enter again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Genie: Genie's Wrath</name>
				<text>Once during each of your turns when you hit with an attack roll, you can deal extra damage to the target equal to your proficiency bonus. The type of this damage is determined by your patron: bludgeoning (dao), thunder (djinni), fire (efreeti), or cold (marid).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Genie: Elemental Gift</name>
				<text>You begin to take on characteristics of your patron's kind. You now have resistance to a damage type determined by your patron's kind: bludgeoning (dao), thunder (djinni), fire (efreeti), or cold (marid).</text>
				<text>	In addition, as a bonus action, you can give yourself a flying speed of 30 feet that lasts for 10 minutes, during which you can hover. You can use this bonus action a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Genie: Sanctuary Vessel</name>
				<text>When you enter your Genie's Vessel via the Bottled Respite feature, you can now choose up to five willing creatures that you can see within 30 feet of you, and the chosen creatures are drawn into the vessel with you.</text>
				<text>	As a bonus action, you can eject any number of creatures from the vessel, and everyone is ejected if you leave or die or if the vessel is destroyed.</text>
				<text>	In addition, anyone (including you) who remains within the vessel for at least 10 minutes gains the benefit of finishing a short rest, and anyone can add your proficiency bonus to the number of hit points they regain if they spend any Hit Dice as part of a short rest there.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Genie: Limited Wish</name>
				<text>You entreat your patron to grant you a small wish. As an action, you can speak your desire to your Genie's Vessel, requesting the effect of one spell that is 6th level or lower and has a casting time of 1 action. The spell can be from any class's spell list, and you don't need to meet the requirements in that spell, including costly components; the spell simply takes effect as part of this action.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish 1d4 long rests.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList name="Warlock (Genie Dao)">
		<index name="Detect Evil and Good" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Force" />
		<index name="Create Food and Water" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Killer" />
		<index name="Creation" />
		<index name="Wish" />
		<index name="Sanctuary" />
		<index name="Spike Growth" />
		<index name="Meld into Stone" />
		<index name="Stone Shape" />
		<index name="Wall of Stone" />
	</spellList>
	<spellList name="Warlock (Genie Djinni)">
		<index name="Detect Evil and Good" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Force" />
		<index name="Create Food and Water" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Killer" />
		<index name="Creation" />
		<index name="Wish" />
		<index name="Thunderwave" />
		<index name="Gust of Wind" />
		<index name="Wind Wall" />
		<index name="Greater Invisibility" />
		<index name="Seeming" />
	</spellList>
	<spellList name="Warlock (Genie Efreeti)">
		<index name="Detect Evil and Good" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Force" />
		<index name="Create Food and Water" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Killer" />
		<index name="Creation" />
		<index name="Wish" />
		<index name="Burning Hands" />
		<index name="Scorching Ray" />
		<index name="Fireball" />
		<index name="Fire Shield" />
		<index name="Flame Strike" />
	</spellList>
	<spellList name="Warlock (Genie Marid)">
		<index name="Detect Evil and Good" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Force" />
		<index name="Create Food and Water" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Killer" />
		<index name="Creation" />
		<index name="Wish" />
		<index name="Fog Cloud" />
		<index name="Blur" />
		<index name="Sleet Storm" />
		<index name="Control Water" />
		<index name="Cone of Cold" />
	</spellList>
</compendium>